Ahmed Khalid

Senior Full Stack Developer

Arlington, TX 76002 ak.aik901@gmail.com +1 682 300 2420

Building web applications since 2012. I am an outcome driven full stack engineer, having a passion for problem solving, building and optimizing user-focused applications. I have led team(s) of 5 - 10 people across technology, business and design departments. I have extensive experience working with modern web frameworks (MEAN, MERN, MEVN etc) and languages including frontend and backend technologies such as React, Angular, GraphQL, Node and Mongo.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Senior Full Stack Developer

ArcTouch - San Francisco, CA April 2017 to Present

- Designed and developed 20+ frontend and backend applications using TypeScript, React, Angular, Vue and Node.
- Developed several application features and distributed services that support high-scale applications.
- Participated in several weekly code reviews to ensure code quality and system system efficiency.
- Ensured performance, quality and responsiveness for several applications.
- Designed and Developed systems architecture designs, patterns and approaches.
- Collaborated with client service teams to understand and solve bottlenecks and proposed feature expansions.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.
- Designed and managed full-stack solutions that solved 70% of use cases from embedded devices and web UI to backend and database.
- Led 12+ successful (on schedule and budget) agile development projects

Full Stack Developer

Rootstrap - West Hollywood, CA June 2014 to March 2017

- Designed and Developed several front-end web interfaces.
- Worked with 8+ teams to build web-based tools to facilitate the team's development life cycle.
- Collaborated with SRE teams to identify issues and increase stability, performance, and efficiency of private computing services.
- Architected, Implemented and Maintained performant and scalable data-processing back-end systems.
- Built pipeline scheduling and execution platform and corresponding front-end to manage and interact with the platform.
- Development and maintenance of new products, technical documentation and workflows.
- Led architecture, design and development of several frontend and backend features.
- Learned organization's overall strategies, business operates, and led projects to success.

- Wrote backend code, integrated with framework and APIs, and utilized multiple CLI tools and configuration GUI's.
- Developed and maintained REST APIs writing documentation using OpenAPI specifications.
- Assisted in requirements analysis, High Level Design, Low Level Design, and complex code development for 10+ applications.
- Developed applications following Agile product development methodologies.

Web Developer

MentorMate - Minneapolis, MN June 2012 to May 2014

- · Collaborated with a team of seven web developers to create sleek and innovative UI designs.
- Identified opportunities to improve efficiency and functionality for servers, databases, and APIS.
- Designed and implemented new product features and web architecture.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.
- Developed landing pages, dashboards and online applications using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and jQuery.
- Designed and established user-friendly websites, including optimized check-out page, resulting in a major increase in user clicks and subsequently impacting in customer purchases.
- Formulated and implemented improvements on cleanup processes and performance, minimizing downtime.
- Established an interactive and dynamic website that guarantees high traffic, page views, and maximum user experience, generating an increase in the company's sales revenue.

Education

Bachelors in Computer Science

Boston University - Boston, MA March 2008 to May 2012

Skills

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React / React Native / Next.js
- Angular / MEAN
- · Vue.js / Nuxt.js
- Node.js, Express.js
- MongoDB, SQL, No SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis ,Microsoft SQL Server.
- HTML,CSS, Bootsrap & Material UI
- GraphQL, REST & SOAP
- AWS, Azure & GCP
- Docker (swarm, Nginx), kubernetes
- C#, ASP.NET (Core & MVC)
- E2E testing (Playwright, Cypress, Puppeteer, Jest)
- jQuery, AJAX
- Python

• Linux, Ubuntu